# Fábio Ferreira

## Frontend Developer

Santarém, Portugal \( +351 927 671 290 \) me@fabiof.dev \( \phi \) fabiof.dev

## Summary

Frontend Developer with over 4 years of professional experience and 6+ years of coding expertise, skilled in both UX/UI design and Fullstack development. With a foundation in design and a career in cybersecurity, I deliver web solutions that combine aesthetics, functionality, and resilience.

For a more detailed view of my work, technologies used and other details, visit my portfolio at https://fabiof.dev

## **Technical Skills**

- Frontend: Typescript, React, NextJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Storybook, MaterialUI, Styled Components
- Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase, RESTful APIs
- Testing: Vitest, Jest, Unit testing, CI/CD pipelines
- Other Tools: Figma, Git, GitLab, Github, Docker, Jira, SonarQube, Windows, Linux

# Work Experience

#### Fullstack Developer & UX/UI Designer | Layer8 - Cybersecurity Company

Aug 2022 - Present

- Lead developer for the company's component library, reducing development time by 50% through reusable, scalable, secure and responsive components.
- Leading the development of a cloud management platform to centralize the company's services, with features such as user and service management using RESTful APIs.
- Contributed significantly to redesigning and restructuring legacy projects to align with the new design guidelines and component library, ensuring 100% design consistency across projects.
- Consulted on security best practices for web applications, minimizing vulnerabilities and improving system reliability.

#### Fullstack Developer & UX/UI Designer | Freelancer

Dez 2021 - Present

- Designed and developed websites focusing on responsive design and performance optimization creating a stronger online presence for clients.
- Produced diverse creative solutions, including graphic design and multimedia projects, delivering 100% client satisfaction through cohesive and polished results.

## Frontend Developer | Gestix - Invoice Company

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

- Rebuilt and redesigned the company's main website, improving performance and user experience by 20%.
- Developed a customizable, UI/UX-friendly website template for clients, Increasing customer satisfaction by 35%.
- Redesigned the back-office interface to improve usability and user experience.

# Fábio Ferreira

## Frontend Developer

Santarém, Portugal 📞 +351 927 671 290 🔀 me@fabiof.dev 🏶 fabiof.dev

## **Projects**

#### Personal Portfolio | fabiof.dev

- Designed and developed a modern, responsive personal portfolio using Next.js 15 (React 19)
- Created detailed wireframes and prototypes with Figma
- Developed a custom npm package for spyscroll functionality, filling a gap for React 19.
- Integrated Lottie animations to enhance user engagement.

## Business Website | Freelance Project - resultadodemestre.pt

- Developed a dynamic business website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Integrated WordPress to allow the client to manage product listings easily.
- Focused on a clean, user-friendly design to effectively showcase available products.

#### **Social Media App** | fabiof.dev/facepalm

- Designed and built a social media app using React Native and Firebase.
- Implemented user authentication, enabling secure login and registration.
- Enabled core features such as post creation, commenting, friend connections, and real-time private messaging for seamless user interaction.

## Education

#### Google UX Design Professional Certificate | Corsera

2023

- Grade: average of 92.19% on all 7 courses
- Certificate: Corsera Certificate Link

#### **Developing Secure Software (LFD121)** | Linux Foundation

2023

• Certificate: Linux Foundation Certificate Link

#### Web Development | ETIC

2019 - 2020

• Grade 18/20

## Multimedia Technician - High School | Multimedia Technician - High School

2016 - 2019

• Grade: 16/20